<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-01T19:06:10+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/samsblog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Samsblog</title><subtitle>I write cricket related blogs over here, going into extreme level details because I love doing that.</subtitle><author><name>Sammith S Bharadwaj</name></author><entry><title type="html">DC V RR, who replaced Wankhede pitch with a Chepauk one?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/16/rrvdc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DC V RR, who replaced Wankhede pitch with a Chepauk one?" /><published>2021-04-16T06:01:23+05:30</published><updated>2021-04-16T06:01:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/16/rrvdc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/16/rrvdc.html">&lt;p&gt;Samson and Pant are the latest to addition to the captains in this league, leading for the first time in this league, so it was always going to be fun looking at how they do. Sanju Samson used to play for Delhi Daredevils(now Capitals) and once Sanju and Pant got together to chase down 209 runs against Gujrat Lions!!!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanju and Pant back then&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/qmAqELw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanju and Pant now&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/hEdDzrK.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now during toss referee was way too quick to take away the coin the moment he told who won, most probably because Sanju tried to take it away last time.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refree must have been like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/le66BFa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when I found out that Jaydev Unadkat was going to play in Wankhede, I did not know what to think about that, paapa of all the places you could play, he was being made to play in Wankhede, where players were being smacked for fun, well he did make me bite my own words, I am not worried about that, if it were up to me, everyone would play, I know that would make the game boring, but for sure would make me happy, if someone proves me wrong, I actually love it, allows to improve your decision making.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As long as game is fun I am happy&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ds6jZ7K.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Delhi made horrendous team selection, I do not think anybody would argue with that.
First they dropped Hetmyer, which can only be justified if you are playing maybe a Sam Billings or something, not if you are playing Rahane and Tom Curran. Now I am not saying Tom Curran is a bad player, he has done well in Australia and England, but he has not done the same in India or UAE, like ever. Lot of people even questioned playing Rahane, but he had bowled really well last time, so I was expecting to do well here too, it was an okay decision to keep Woakes.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ponting when Pant told his plan to play Hetty at number 3&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/EytDoCz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when everyone was expecting a big 200 score and only 2 runs came of the first over, it was kind of worrying, but it was fine because they would smash it in the end, well it got even worse, the second over was bowled by Unadkat and he bowled really really well, he changed up the pace last ball of the over which Shaw did not read, tried to play across nicked and got caught at backward point. Now this freaked out half of internet, I could smell it, it was going to be a really good game.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/af3hGs9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delhi attacked a little, scoring 11 runs in the third over, but the first ball of 4th over, Dhawan tried to scoop one and Sanju caught it!!!! That probably was the catch of the game, almost a “Dinesh Karthik:, yes I call it that. Now the second ball to Pant was even more incredible, almost caught an edge off of Pant, extremely good bowling.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nVAVSCS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/vIiFye3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At end of 4th over RR are 20/2, worst position ever, there was a stat that Delhi and Rajasthan have lost most wickets in powerplay since last season IPL. 5th over went for 11 runs, what do I talk about it, nothing speacial happened there. 31/2 at this stage.
Now its the 6th over of powerplay and they have gone back with Unadkat, for his third straight over and guess what he did, got wicket of Rahane, he was supposed to save Delhi from these situations, which is one of the main reasons people want players like Rahane to be in team, to save team from collapse, what to do when they are the ones who are part of the collapse, Rahane has failed to save Delhi from a collapse, multiple times now, which is really sad to see, given how much I love the him and the team, but I love RR more, so I did not mind it this time.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When Rahane got out and realising he probably won’t be played from now after this&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Gxni6z6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rajasthan have 3 left arm bowlers this game, the third one being Mustafizur, he was brought for the 7th over. Now he is also a Unadkat type bowler, who relies a lot on those slower ones. He did bowl brilliantly, he rattled Stoinis with 3 dot balls. Now if I am a batsman who has faced 3 dot balls, I am not only under immense pressure, I am going through hell right there, 3 balls is like 2.5% of the innings without scoring nothing continuously is a crime I would never want to commit, that is the perfect opportunity for a bowler to attack the guy with whichever your weapon is. It was full length which Stoinis tried to kind of defend but right went up? I don’t know how it went up, but it did, Buttler caught a brilliant catch.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mustafizur has had a way better season start than expected from him&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/z74jk5A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8th over was bowled by Morris and went for 9 runs, the most important bowler of the group was leaking runs, maybe an indication that slow change of pace deliveries were working better than higher pace ones.
Delhi are at 46/4 by the way, worst possible position to be in.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parag bowled the 9th, he is one of those guys who will do anything to survive, he is the proper definition of survival of the fittest along side Krunal Pandya, do everything you can to do make sure runs are not scored. So obviously Parag had to bring out the “Jadhav ball”, yes I call it that, I am not good at names.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will show this every time he bowls, if he does it everytime also I do not care, its amazing and you have to see it&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Zl3UB1s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now at this point, only established batsman in Pant, Lalit yadav is good player but has never played in IPL, so having high expectations on his is not advisable, Woakes and Tom Curran have batting skills but the same, cannot expect stuff from them, if they play well then well and good.
With 11 overs remaining, Pant has to play an innings like what “Rahane would”, also he needs to aggressive because “he is an aggressive batsman, what is the point of having one if he doesn’t”, he cannot get out hitting sixes because he will be called “irresponsible for doing that”.
Well he kind of delivered, when nobody was able to score a single run, he chose his opponents wisely and smacked Tewatia all over the place, brought up a 30 ball 50!!
He was so good, his innings ended because of a fielding brilliance by Parag, if not for that direct hit I wonder what else Pant would have done, but we need to stop living in hindsight, lets get to the present here. DC were 89/5 here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this DC innings lost track a little, were not able to score runs at all. By the end of 15th over even Lalit Yadav got out leaving Delhi at 102/6.
Now what was the par score for them? You could expect at least 30 more, I would probably would have said 40 more, because Curran, Woakes and Ashwin are capable batsman.
I was very close to getting it right as Delhi got to a 147.
It was mostly simply whacking and mad running in last 3 overs which got them there.
They also played some really nice shots, not denying that.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2EMnqBo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think about it Samson was brilliant as a captain out there, made perfect use of Unadkat, the weak point for Unadkat has always been his death bowling, not saying he was good at other stages, he struggled there also, but we had seen him bowling some really good spells at start and give it away at death.
When asked at what stage do you think you will win the game he was like “I would love to win it by the end of 10th over but I am not a batsman”, what a guy!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if you thought it was going to be a simple chase you were far far far away from being right. Woakes and Avesh were bowling perfect length almost rattling the batsmen.
Only 5 runs came off the first two overs.
The third over was a big one and the architect was:
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/BpNEwiv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two balls were smacked by Manan Vohra for fours, it was looking like RR were about start the attack, but nope!! Vohra couldn’t connect it properly and it went to hands of Rabada.
Worst possible thing that could happen happened just 2 balls later with Chris Woakes banging one in swinger at length, took off the edge of Buttler and dead.
If you thought misery was over, it was only going to get worse, Rabada was brought in for the 3rd over he got the wicket of Samson on the 3rd ball itself. Worse was getting “worser”(I make up words too).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RR fans were like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nNqUORz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sad-jetha-meme&quot;&gt;sad jetha meme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let me talk about the guy about whom I did not talk at all till now, who is David Miller. He was the go to guy for Kings 11 Punjab(now Punjab kings) for three years from 2013-15, after which he could never replicate it in later years.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/0uO6bwE.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was coming off a really good form in ODI where his skills have never been doubted. He also recently brought a game alive for South Africa out of nowhere in a t20 game in Pakistan too. RR ended their powerplay with score 26/3 which is just absolutely terrible. When a team takes 3 wickets in powerplay more often than not, that team wins, but what to do when both teams lost 3 wickets.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/5VGLRsp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it was time for AshWin, Ash anna is one of those guys to whom, slight sniff of a victory is enough to choke you down. He absolutely strangled them giving away just 14 runs in his 3 overs. We also saw 2 wickets fall in the overs between his.
Tom Curran was brought in for the 12th over and even he gave just 2 runs. 58/5 at the end of 12 overs. Required run rate shot up to 11, 2 left handers, there was no reason why Ashwin should not have been bowled. But Pant decided to bowl Stoinis, maybe to get over with one Stoinis over, but it wasn’t really needed, what was needed was getting done with the game as soon as possible, as we have seen anything can happen at death.
Stoinis came and Miller was extremely happy, scored 3 consecutive 4s. 15 runs came of that over, rrr came down to 10.7, it was not looking bad, somehow.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pant to Stoinis&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RlnOuAM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next Tom Curran over game away 12 runs, rrr down to 10.5, were Rajasthan going to make a comeback? They were on their way to but Rabada is one big problem, man came and took the wicket of Rahul Tewatia. Now the target was 58 from 30 balls, not impossible, but not easy also, the thing in favor was that Rabada had only one over.
Now Miller looked at Avesh Khan, it was the perfect opportunity for him to take the game on, shifting it towards the end and he did, he smacked 2 consecutive sixes. We do not know if Tom Curran how good or bad Tom Curran will be, we don’t know if Woakes will give any easy balls, it was the perfect opportunity for Miller to get as far ahead as possible, he tried to hit one more six, but he didn’t time it well, he got out, he was heavily criticised by commentators for going for another six, but that is wrong mindset, if he had got out trying for 2nd six they probably would have been like he doesn’t have ability only to finish off games, &lt;strong&gt;PLEASE CHANGE YOUR MINDSET PA, THAT WAS THE OVER AND CHANCE RR HAD TO GO FAR FAR AHEAD OF DELHI&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Tlr7fsw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 17th over we saw Unadkat hit a six to Woakes, after he had just said he was not a batsman this happens, brilliant!!!
Tom Curran was brilliant, actually Unadkat was almost run out on the first ball of 18th over, because he slipped while going back but lucky for him even Pant dropped the ball while running him out. Only 7 runs came of that over.
&lt;br /&gt;
The slow ball craze was so much that in the 19th over even Rabada tried to bowl, which he should not have because Morris a very big bully, anything to near as easy ball will always go out of the ground and that is what happened. He smoked another six on the 5th ball of over, right out of the middle of the bat by the way. 15 runs came of the over, game completely turned around, Morris even had the strike in the last over.
They still could have gone with Ashwin, RR needed 12 and Morris has had his fair share of struggles against spin bowling, but they persisted with Tom Curran and the poor guy was thrashed by Morris, he tried a slower one(WHY IS EVERYONE TRYING ONE, IT JUST DOES NOT WORK FOR SOME PEOPLE). 4th ball was a yorker gone wrong which he nailed it to perfection for a six and he did it for them!!!!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;to those who bowl slower balls like their main delivery and less like a variation&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ecm2eDD.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;36 off 18, 16.25Cr absolutely worth it.
When teams are ready to pay you that much amount of big money, the expectations are to win you at least 3-4 games or 1-2 games like these, not everyone can do that and if you do, you will be paid the big bucks for sure.
&lt;br /&gt;
Now I know, a lot of you will be like Sanju should have taken a single, dude do you know what Morris himself said? He said he wanted to take a double, even he knew obviously Sanju should have been on strike, what he did not realise was there was no way Sanju could have run back a 2nd run.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things sometimes work out, sometimes don’t, stop living in hindsight&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/BPyYKfS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main takeaways and fun stuff:
Sanju has some next level confidence on his team as well as his players, when asked why he chose bowling, he was like because I have faith in bowlers, “I don’t mind them going for runs, we will come and hit them.”
At the end when Sanju was asked if he thinks about games and if he would have run that single he said, “yes, I always think about the game and even if I played that game 100 times I would not have run that single”, extreme clarity in his thought process.
Pant has evolved to a next level beast now.
I don’t know if I love Parag more of his dance more.
Rajasthan are enjoying their game a lot and I love it.
RR can probably think of opening with Miller.
Anything happens anyday, happiness somehow reaches Morgan, this time is Chris Woakes.
Even Ponting did agreed that Ashiwn should have been bowled for teh foutth over, but its fine, they will hopefully learn from their mistakes, anyway with that team selection they should not have won, that would’ve eencouraged doing such nonsense now and again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sammith S Bharadwaj</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Samson and Pant are the latest to addition to the captains in this league, leading for the first time in this league, so it was always going to be fun looking at how they do. Sanju Samson used to play for Delhi Daredevils(now Capitals) and once Sanju and Pant got together to chase down 209 runs against Gujrat Lions!!!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RCB V SRH, when Glenn is performing its Max-Well</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/15/RCBVSRH.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RCB V SRH, when Glenn is performing its Max-Well" /><published>2021-04-15T05:01:23+05:30</published><updated>2021-04-15T05:01:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/15/RCBVSRH</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/15/RCBVSRH.html">&lt;p&gt;Chennai has been one the weirdest pitches like ever and it got even weird this time. Very few people have been able to consistently hit the ball at death overs which include ABD, Dinesh Karthik and today Glenn Maxwell!!! In 2nd innings, make that only ABD. Funniest thing is there was a report that said Chennai pitches will be suited for high scores this season.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chennai curators be like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4iShDjj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets get to the toss, evidence suggests that Kohli loses 60% of tosses, which way lower than we portray it to be, but still 60 is a high number, so when SRH won the toss it wasn’t a surprise for even Kohli.
If we had to look at past games for evidence I would say that, you are way better batting 1st over 2nd, pitch gets way too way too quickly, as we saw how MI had kept a test match field yesterday to Russel!! Russel of all people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/fufuUX2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing about Kohli is, he is very secretive about a lot of stuff which is none of my business by the way but at the same, sometimes he is way too open, gives away IPL strategies even before starts, release team sheets a day before match, when presenter asks who is playing, not only tell him Devdutt is playing, also tell off who is batting at number 3. Warner talked about how he has brought in Nadeem to attack a right hander heavy RCB top order, so to my eyes Kohli was being like, “oh you think you got it right, wait till you see my move son!!” completely throwing off SRH strategy.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RfrqmM0.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is extremely important as a team to have a strong aggressive start at the Chepauk, because it doesn’t seem like anybody will ever make runs at death(well someone will eventually figure it out), which is why when Paddikal got out on 5th ball of 3rd with score of 19 I was bit worried if they would try to be aggressive or try to save wickets, but luckily as Shahbaz Ahmed was sent they could peacefully afford to keep attacking and that is what they kind of did, the over of Holder was next which only went for 6 runs, but the next 2 after that returned 21 runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About those two overs, 5th were bowled by Shahbaz Nadeem, so we witnessed a Shahbaz v Shahbaz battle after all. Nadeem tried to bowl a Krunal Pandya like yorker at his legs but missed the line, which meant Ahmed scooped one for a six. In the RCB V MI game, one of the announcer called Shahbaz Ahmed as Nadeem, so what I am think is when that guy saw these two play, he must’ve thought why is same guy batting as well as bowling.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ihcTw5y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
By the end of end of powerplay i.e the 6th over, RCB were 47/1, not the perfect start, not a bad start, just your average slightyly above average powerplay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7th over was kind of match turning, its funny because the bowler was also a turner(Ashton Turner approves this joke). Shahbaz Ahmed tried to take on Nadeem immediately but fell short as he was caught out and only 1 run came of that over!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now at this point Star Sports select dugout is talking about Maxwell and will he be successful this IPL, Scott Styris talked about how he has adjusted his technique such that when he gets a chance to play a lofted cover drive, he does not carve the ball, instead comes into proper position and drives it properly.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;just a select dugout appreciation that is all&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eSRXk5L.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Warner brought Rashid Khan for the 8th over and it was going to be brilliant as Maxwell was also there, if you think about it, the perfect moment here would be Maxwell showing off his technique change to smash Rashid for a boundary and that’s what exactly happened. Only 7 runs came of the over, but its Rashid, take any boundary you get.
&lt;br /&gt;
The next 2 overs were not really the most productive with only 3 and 5 runs coming of Nadeem and Rashid. The whole of last season RCB had one big issue which was they slowed down a lot in after powerplay and it was worrying to see what was happening here.
&lt;br /&gt;
But we had Maxwell ma! Took the game on on the 11th over bowled by Nadeem, pull over midwicket for a six, lofter cover drive for four, pull over midwicket for six again, 16 runs in no time. Total of 22 runs came of that over, suddenly RCB run rate went from 6.3 to 7.72. It was superb hitting.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the joy was only temporary because SRH completely choked us for the next 6 overs. Holder got the wicket of Kohli first ball of 12th. He was brilliant, did not give any chance to score runs at all and only gave away 1 run. This was the second time this game an over going for only one run as well as losing a wicket on the first ball of over.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RCB fans throughout the game&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/lvx4Ppr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Rashid was brought back for 14th over and he got the wicket of ABD, it was looking awful for us, went from strong position to weak to a solid one to a really bad one.
RCB were 103/4 at the end of 15th over, not the strongest position to be in, one luckily RCB has an immense batting depth.
Rashid bowled the 16th over and got wicket of Sundar who got out trying to play a no look six. That over also went for only 3 runs and if that was not enough, next over natarajan took wicket of Christian(my x-factor) and only gave 4 runs.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me and my friends after Christian got out&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RAB9Pky.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most important thing still was that Maxwell was still not out, he was still there. Jamieson and Maxwell together nailed Bhuvaneshwar in the 17th over, scoring 3 4s and a total of 14 runs.
19th over was by Nattu and 12 runs came off of it, it was looking really good for RCB. Maxwell played one of Maxwellest shots on a yorker, he tried to bowl a wide yorker but it became a sort of wide one, Maxwell almost sat, switch his bat and scooped one over for a four. Even on the last ball, Maxwell did not care, instead of what most people would do take a single, he attacked. Jamieson in the final over tried to slog but got caught, but the important thing was Maxwell was brought back on strike.
Maxwell was fixed that he was not going to run if there wasn’t a 2, for some reason Holder was not trying to do the wide yorker plan which all the teams love so much. He learnt he had to bowl wider deliveries after Maxwell crunched one for a massive, massive six. He did get out trying to reach a wide one, but scored around 13 runs of the last over which in that pitch was golden.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now the game won on!! 150 was not enough but it definitely was to give a challenge&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/af3hGs9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SRH innings started, RCB gave the first over to Siraj and boy he bowled well, like really really well, nipping, swinging, Saha was clueless, unlucky that the last ball was a leg byes for four, but anyway he got a maiden over. Siraj got rewards for his bowling in the second over taking wicket of Saha but the thing was he was never the main threat, two guys in this SRH team have ability to crush us and were still not out with batting were Warner and Bairstow and Warner was looking in supreme touch too, batting ultra aggresively, SRH went to 50/1 at the end of powerplay and Warner was batting at a strike rate of over 200!! Some guy on twitter tweeted that only Warner can bat on Sharjah like its Chennai and bat like its Chennai in Sharjah which was just too good.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/aICuFLQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing which still bothers me is not using Sundar in powerplay, maybe Kohli is trying to groom his as a middle over specialist for Indian team, but we have Chahal for that ma, he is brilliant there, use Sundar where he is really really good in powerplay, if you want to groom him you can anyway give one over to him there. RCB did not really have the best of powerplays to justify not bowling Sundar.
&lt;br /&gt;
RCB took the required run rate which was at 7.14 at the end of powerplay to all the way up to 7.71, you might think arey 7.71 is manageable, no ma it is not, required run rate had claimed to almost what it was required before SRH innings started which is terrible given that death overs were about to start where nobody had scored any runs.(Now saying death over was about to start is just a fancy way of saying as we reach end pitch becomes difficult to bat that’s all)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t leave everything to the end of innings, very difficult to score at death.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/N2KA8hG.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What would be the most terrible thing to happen here? You guessed it right Warner getting out, and he did. Kyle Jamieson did not have the best first two overs but he more than made up for it in his 3rd over. He only gave 6 runs in the over including leg byes. The only threat really was Jonny Bairstow, if RCB somehow got his wicket game was over, it was not going to be easy for him though, it was a really difficult pitch to bat on. The next 2 overs of Ahmed and Chahal went for only 13 runs which was superb for RCB.
SRH needed 35 of 24 balls and the biggest twist happened here. Virat brought in Shahbaz Ahmed, slow left armers have been proven to be very effective here, Krunal yesterday, Nadeem today apart from that carnage over where Maxwell went berserk, so it was kind of a nice move by Kohli and it paid of brilliantly because he got 2 in 2, the first two balls of the over were wickets, that too big ones, Bairstow and Pandey, he did not stop there, he got another wicket in the final ball of the over, giving away only one run and taking 3 big big wickets!! Now the equation being 34 of 18 ball.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRH fans at that moment&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3UkiHKi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RCB fans at that moment&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/XmmyaeI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shahbaz Ahmed&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/k1P6yhQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harshal Patel whose role for has been the death over specialist has paid off really well with him controlling really well, giving away only 7 runs and even taking wicket of Vijay Shankar.
Now for the 19th over Virat had 2 choices either go with Ahmed or Siraj, now both were risky ones, sla have been effective but if you are good enough spin hitter you can be taken down shown by Maxwell, Siraj is because he has not been the best bowler at death and we have seen Rashid Khan do crazy stuff to bowlers even to established death bowlers but it was a bold move and he we #playbold. Rashid hit a six of the first ball itself and “yella bayig bandbidtu”, but then he got the wicket of Holder 2 balls later and they scored 11 runs of the over. Full excitement and thrills, there was no way RCB could lose that game but there has been long history of that happening, so nothing was certain, oh! what a rush.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/7DYwF0Y.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now with Harshal Patel bowling last over, it was a hopeful that he would pull it off, but on the 3rd ball, his hands slipped and a full toss no ball, oh hell!!! after doing so much so well, this happens, IPL man, not for the light hearted, but luckily he pulled it off, free hit was a dot ball, it was really good change of pace which made him miss it, Rashid got out the immediate ball after that and all was well and good after that, game was done and dusted with even Nadeem getting out on the 5th ball.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After that no ball&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/9YeqJdS.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main takeaways and fun stuff:
Shahbaz Nadeem and Shahbaz Ahmed when facing each other is always fun.
I can’t watch Manish Pandey like this man, love him so much, used to be so good too, was brilliant in last SMAT too. Never really got to his own since he got to SRH, just don’t know why, maybe the 11cr price pressure or using him various different roles or his own limitations, I don’t know but I want it to change.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/yPROP7C.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Maxwell has found his perfect match, Maxwell is a guy who is a guy who is perfectly suited to destroy bowling lineups, you cannot expect him to give you 600-700 run seasons every year, he is not that kind of player, but what he can give you 400-450 run seasons at 155 strike rate and do not underestimate those players, those are the guys who win you games from impossible situations. I mean there is always a chance he will go on to make 650 runs at 150 SR but that is not something you can expect consistently.
RCB is one of the team for whom that kind of an overseas player is gold and they are in my opinion bringing the best out of him.
Harshal is turning out to be the go to man this season
Rashid is a legend, he will definitely be the all time great t20 spinner.
RCB games are always close, heart in mouth all the time, so Ravi Shastri has to be called all the time to summarise it.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/03akP1T.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This much I can tell for sure, KKR camp will be a lot happier after looking at this game.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/5zNyR4h.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sammith S Bharadwaj</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Chennai has been one the weirdest pitches like ever and it got even weird this time. Very few people have been able to consistently hit the ball at death overs which include ABD, Dinesh Karthik and today Glenn Maxwell!!! In 2nd innings, make that only ABD. Funniest thing is there was a report that said Chennai pitches will be suited for high scores this season.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MI V KKR, a lesson on how not to collapse</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/14/MIVKKR.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MI V KKR, a lesson on how not to collapse" /><published>2021-04-14T00:12:23+05:30</published><updated>2021-04-14T00:12:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/14/MIVKKR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/14/MIVKKR.html">&lt;p&gt;The main talking point before a MI V KKR is always the scoreline that KKR just can’t beat MI, a 78% success rate is too high over a peariod of 13 years. But this time it was different, KKR had a better captain, they had better players than last time, they were better prepared, they even won the toss.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KKR fans must have been like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/af3hGs9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets talk teams, best part of MI V KKR matches with Morgan and Sharma ji as captains is predicting playing 11, they just never change and even the changes they are always obvious. And the only obvious change was QDK in for Lynn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Rohit struggles with spin as well as QDK being a left hander who struggles with off spin too, it would not have been the worst decision to start with Bhajji and Chakravarthi.
Bhajji made extreme utility giving away just 3 runs, clearly the strategy here was to choke run flow and let wicket come by itself and it did in the last ball of 2nd over itself. Now here both right hand batsman, Rohit and Suryakumar, but Morgan for some reason chose to go with Bhajji, who was taken for cleaners by SKY, with 14 runs coming of that over. In the 4th over Shakib was brought in a profitable matchup as there were 2 right handers.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morgan be like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/t1NfR1q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now only 42 runs came off the pwoerply but MI would not really have worried about that.
now what had been a slow and steady batting till now, SKY took down Shami brilliantly, smoking a 6,4,4. SKY was batting beautifully and it peaked in the 10th over, Cummins bowled a good length delivery which SKY look it literally to the SKY!! It was a 99m six, which went straight onto the roof, it was majestic, it was magnificent, it was 50 in style.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I can guarantee this was reaction of Suryakumar&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/k1P6yhQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But the better reaction was from Pandya&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eSRXk5L.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The high did not last long though as he found himself catch the immediate over after that. Now I know I have been quite silent about Sharma ji, yes I know that but that is because there isn’t much to talk about him, by the end of the over he only had faced 20 balls, he was playing second fiddle the whole time, giving strike back to SKY and enjoying from the best place to be in, non strikers end.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/XU8KQby.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And then the choking started, KKR absolutely bamboozled MI, not allowing singles, doubles or boundaries, PAT FRICKIN CUMMINS yesterday proved that is why it is really worth spending hefty amounts over. not only did he take wicket, he also ensured there was no way MI would score runs, only 6 runs came off of the 12th and 13over
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Vf4Beit.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14th over was by Prasidh Krishna of the innings was super productive for MI, with him bowling a short one to Rohit Sharma. What was he even thinking, KKR were so nicely bamboozling Sharma, he did not look in flow at all.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jvgzVI2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cummins came in at the 16th over and changed the game again for them, again! where he not only took the wicket of Sharma ji who never looked comfortable yesterday, he only gave 6runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morgan brought in the big GUN Russel into the attack, now the thing Russel is a complete utility player, tell him something to do, he will do that to perfection, he is an extremely smart bowler, he kept coming in from round the wicket and bowling outside off stump, he was extremely successful getting 2 wickets as well as giving away only 5 runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MI managed to score 12 runs of the 19th over bowled by Prasidh Krishna, which included a 4 leg byes. Russel came back for the last over, which was too good, Krunal smacked 2 consecutive 4s of the first over and it kind of reminded me of 2017 IPL final, MI at a below par score and Krunal smacking it in the last over, but it did not last long as he got out 3rd delivery. The over was so funny, Russel got 2 more wickets and in total he went for 10 runs.
So at the end of 20 overs MI were 152 all out, with Russel taking a 5-fer by bowling just 2 overs.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Russel after taking a 5fer in just 2 overs&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bKvhKn3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was kind of an underwhelming innings by MI, last 2 games MI have been terrible in the death overs while batting, which is probably their strongest suit, hopefully it comes back because I really want to see Llord and Pandya’s toying with other bowling lineups.
KKR looked pretty good by the end of powerplay having scored 45, after a slow start Gill had started getting it on, scoring 3 fours in the 6th over.
But one thing was already evident, Krunal Pandya was going to extract everything that is possible to extract fom the wicket, in the first over, he completely utilised the matchup which was in complete favour of him while bowling to Shubhman.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right hand batsmen ko bowling karna&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/hJOEdI3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KKR openers were looking pretty solid and after 8th over which was bowled by Pollard they even took the required run lower than their current run rate.
The next over was pure gold, Chahar dropped it short and Gill smashed one for four, 4th ball of the over Gill crushed it over long on for a maximum, but the immediate ball after that Chahar bowled kind of a similar, just that it was swalpa fuller, swalpa wider and also swalpa quicker and it went straight to hand of the Llord. Now when asked about it in the post match presentation, he said he has known Shubhman from u-19 age and he knows Gill can’t keep hitting continious sixes which gives him a chance to try to give him “lalach” and maybe get a wicket.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maybe Mumbai’s another mantra is “agar lalach dikhane se wicket mil jaye to lalach is cool”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/1dgY5XE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chahar has always been used as a middle overs bowlers, very similar to as a Yuzi Chahal, who has been doing successfully for RCB for a long time and that’s what he did, he bowled all his overs on the trot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of 10th over, GG in Star Sports select dugout said, if someone can do the job for MI, it has to be a leg spinner and it was turning out to be true, not all things he says are jinx ma. GG’s words always come true for MI
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gg watching MI losing the game&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/0yqQiPx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In the 10th over which was Chahar’s 2nd, it spun amazingly well and caught the outside edge, it was a proper leg break wicket, pitching towards outside leg, spinning all the way towards off stump, catching the edge while batsman tries to dab it or cut or whatever he tries to do.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batsmen after getting out to classic leg spin&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RfrqmM0.jpg?1&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GG was also talking about how there are very few leg spinners who bowl proper leg spin, they mainly bowl googlies and even their leg spinners don’t spin that much so its always better to play them as an off spinner, which is kind of a good plan, because at most you will get beaten and look like an idiot, but not get out.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/5pvxtev.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pressure was building up but kind of got released in the Bumrah over, which went for 12 runs, can you imagine, I mean 5 runs were leg byes but still runs are runs, doesn’t matter if they get added to bowlers stats or not. Morgan even played an incredible a brilliant ramp shot in that over too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 13th over, Chahar had already gone for 7 runs in 4 balls, which was the required run rate at that stage, but Morgan’s dil mange more and he went for a slog and got caught out, which was kind of becoming like the worst case scenario because, with Shakib the only left hander remaining to come to join Rana, MI did not have a single off spinner and all the batsman coming next were right handers, Krunal had 2 overs left and he would eat them alive which is exactly what he did. KKR need 49 of 42 balls at this point.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KKR fans who knew one more collapse was coming in&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ds6jZ7K.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it was the 13th over, with 2 left handed batsman batting, extreme assistance available to spinners and also not wanting to use up Bumrah, what is the obvious thing that MI would do you can think of? Bowl Sharma ji and it happened, I was tripping so hard when I saw him coming to bowl, I was not the only one who tripped, even Sharma ji tripped and hurt his ankle, all my laughter taken away from me in mere seconds, Jayawardene was up, full in shock, thinking what happened man.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eDkcnlh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/9YeqJdS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was fine only, he came back and bowled an absolute beauty, Shakib edged it and almost got bowled but as luck would have, it went full behind for four, all other balls went for a single, ended the weirdest strategy that almost worked over. It was Sharma ji bowling in IPL after 7 long years. At this point KKR need 40 off 36 balls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last over Sharma ji bowled a beauty and it went for four, you would think luck cannot be bad to MI again, but nope!! It was, another beauty from Chahar went behind for four, very sad for MI given how good they were bowling those overs. But the over ended on a high because on the last ball of the over in which they had already got 9 runs and required run rate being 6, Nitish Rana came down the track, Chahar saw it coming, bowled full away from him and got a wicket. It was looking like a terrible collapse was incoming.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/sOJMh51.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krunal was brought back, till that point he had been absolutely brilliant but from this point it going to get even better.
Shakib tried to slog and got caught out, with 6 being rrr he was slogging which absolutely crushed the select dugout people, they were freaking out left and right about what KKR were doing.
Only 1 run came off that over.
Krunal dropped one from Russel too which came straight to him. At this point the field settings are extremely aggressive Pollard standing in front with his helmet on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Something similar had happened once&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/OrrDXIB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean 16th over of an innings going for one run.
Russel looked so so nervous when Krunal was bowling, he was defending them, dude Krunal is the smartiest pants you will ever witness.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Russel so uncomfortable got all MI fans like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/XmmyaeI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now 17th required run rate came up to 7.5 and Bumrah still had 2 more overs remaining, everyone on twitter was freaking, everyone in dugout was freaking out, I was freaking out, Russel was giving respect to Bumrah and backing himself to score of other 2 overs, even though one was of Krunal but still and Bumrah did the worst thing possible, bowl a no ball, free hit went for a over, but not a big problem, only 8 runs came of the over but gave KKR a little bit of breathing space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now in Krunal’s over, 3rd ball of the over Russel tried to smack it, it went long the way up near Bumrah and he put it down!!!!! It was like, did he drop the match? But Krunal was not going to get demoralised and lose concentration, that’s how this team is, extremely supportive of each other, understand mistakes happen, maybe give a reaction here and there but completely forget about it after that. Only 3 runs of the over, and he ended his spell at 4-0-13-1 wicket, one of the best bowling spells ever which did not get as much appreciation as much as other stuff got.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Krunal watching Bumrah drop a catch&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/yPROP7C.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that it was classic Bumrah stuff, choke the batsman, bowl perfect yorkers, bowl wide off the stump to DK because he tries to do that and beat him, change pave to make batsman look like a fool, do everything possible to not give a run. Only 4 of the over and Boult had 15 runs to defend. Game was still not over, because on clean hit and game in on, but Boult did not lose calm, bowled incredibly, strangled Russel by bowling to his feel and caught and bowled him. The next delivery was an absolute ripper of a yorker to bowl Cummins out. Only 4 runs came of that over to seal a 10 run win for MI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craziest game to ever be a part of, MI took their lead over KKR to 22-6. Interestingly though, in 2009 Rohit Sharma scored 22 runs of the last over to win a game for Decccan Chargers in 2009
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dDtv1qh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main takeaways and fun stuff:
I absolutely love that Varun and DK will always be talking in tamil
When 3rd umpire have a simple run out decision very quickly he was like “last year umpires woful check 3 different replays of the same video”.
Trent Boult might not replicate his heroics from last season but he will for sure give do it here or there once in a while.
Bumrah used inflate deflate strategy to perfection here, inflating by dropping catch and bowling no ball and deflating by doing what he does best when absolutely necessary.
There needs to be a communication between players and Morgan about the aggressive batting, because yes he wants them to play aggressive brand of cricket, but this trying to be so aggressive, it even freaked Morgan out. He obviously doesn’t want players to keep smashing when not possible. This is a note for others also who troll Morgan for what KKR did
The amount of faith and support MI show towards their players is unreal man, absolutely love it, when player himself says captain has more faith in me than myself, you know its a happy camp.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharma ji when MI starts losing to KKR&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/mUSysW8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sammith S Bharadwaj</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">The main talking point before a MI V KKR is always the scoreline that KKR just can’t beat MI, a 78% success rate is too high over a peariod of 13 years. But this time it was different, KKR had a better captain, they had better players than last time, they were better prepared, they even won the toss.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PBKS V RR, we love you Sanju</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/13/PBKSVRR.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PBKS V RR, we love you Sanju" /><published>2021-04-13T07:12:23+05:30</published><updated>2021-04-13T07:12:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/13/PBKSVRR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/13/PBKSVRR.html">&lt;p&gt;I am a guy who is heavily biased towards English criketers, I absolutely love them and given Rajasthan Royals is filled with English influence, it won’t come as a surpise whom I was supporting today, but enough of my preference, lets get to the game here.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All the English players after reading this&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/x8p69Vk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manan Vohra was finally handed the cap after waiting for one long year, which was nice to see. Chetan Sakariya, Morris as well Mustafizur were debuting for RR. Punjab decided to go with most obvious overseas choice Gayle, Pooran, Meridth and Jhye. Rajasthan won the toss and chose to field first on realy good batting surface of Wankhede.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us talk about the background stuff, now KL Rahul has been ly criticised by people for scoring at lower strike rate than he is capable of, Sanju Samson had been named the captain so would be interesting to see how he would perform there. 2 captains, 2 different things to prove.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/af3hGs9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The first stat which was shown was that Rahul had the higest average in the powerplay, one of the most important thing we need to remember is that just preserving wicket in the powerplay is not the only thing you need to do, you also need to attack, score needs to be extremely high. Now KL had a great season after which his SR has dipped, second on list was Gill whose sample size is low and also his innings did not help the min winning or losing, the third person on the list was Warner who averages 67 in pp, he not only averages well there, he also strikes at a very healthy rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PBKS started off really well scoring 21 runs of the first 2 overs, but then Chetan Sakariya, the debutant got the wicket of Mayank in the 3rd over, Mayank probably could’ve moved less away from the leg stump, which wouldn’t have caused him to knick it. PBKS kept it low key after that reaching 46/1 at the end of 6 overs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After powerplay Shreyas Gopal was brought in, Rahul almost played it into the hands of ben Stokes, who made an incredible effort to catch it by the, just couldn’t hold onto it. 12 runs came off the over, given Gopal could’ve gotten wicket of Rahul, that’s just too sad.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shreyas Gopal’s face literally was like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VpA5IL5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gayle and Rahul started taking the bowlers on with then scoring 12 runs in each of the three overs from 7th to 9th overs. Then came in Riyan Parag to bowl the 10th over, you would think after being hit for four the first would demoralise him and Punjab would try to score some 10-15 runs of the over, but Parag was super smart out there, to counter being attacked, he even bowled a delivery like Kedar Jadhav which was too funny to watch. There have been other players too who have done that including Krunal and Manoj Tiwari.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Zl3UB1s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jnuJvz8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/KFFHEZH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had seen glimpses of aggressive batting from Punjab here till now, but still they were what, 89/2 at the end of 10 overs, which is a great platform to start belting and boy oh boy did Punjab Kings belt Rajasthan bowlers.
One thing to note here was Deepak Hooda came into batting instead of Pooran which was a decision Punjab and let me just spoil it for you here, it come off incredibly well for them.
They scored 13 and 8 runs off of 11th and 12th which is just a start here, because the next 13th and 14th overs went for 20 runs each.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rajasthan bowlers were like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jD39LZ1.jpg&quot;&gt;Imgur&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13th over was bowled by Shivam Dube, Rahul even brought up his half century of just 30 balls, after all this stupid strike rate nonsense, both by him as well as us, he finally played aggressively only.
But Deepak Hooda, he was at a different level, there was a time long time ago when Deepak Hooda had played a very similar ultra aggressive innings when he was playing for Rajasthan Royals.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/yKMn9Az.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most astonishing part was how upset Hooda got about himself for getting beaten by the ball immediately after he had smashed a six.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14th over was by Gopal and Hooda had made his intentions extremely clear here, he smoked 3 sixes in that over. The next 3 overs were super productive too, a total of 37 runs coming off of it.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hooda to Rajasthan bowlers was like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/PwSlY5r.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deepak Hooda even brought up his fifty in just 20 balls, one of most eye catching innings in IPL. Then came the most eventful over of them all.
Morris was bowling the 18th over Rahul scooped one for a six the first delivery itself. Morris even got the wicket of Hooda after Rahul gave him the strike.
Then Rahul came back to strike Hood and Rahul had crossed and Rahul smoked another on for six, he was all over Morris’ head at that point.
Then on the final ball Nicholas Pooran tried to pull on towards fine leg but Chetan Sakariya took an absolute stunner to catch him out.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catch pakadna&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/hJOEdI3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 19th over went for 15 runs, Punjab were already at 216/4 out there.
But we were about witness some incredible death over bowling by Sakariya. Rahul got out after scoring 91 runs off the second ball, would’ve been an incredible century though.
Only 5 runs came of the over and also 2 wickets, dream debut for Sakariya and Punjab managed to score 221 runs of the 20 overs.
Rahul Tewatia’s catch of KL Rahul incredible, amazing how they pull of these boundary catches and miss simple ones.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batsman watching shots which were supposed to go for six being caught&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/le66BFa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Rajasthan Royals batting innings had the funniest starts ever. Ben Stokes tried to loft but it edged and by the time it came back down, Rahul, Shami and Hooda all three were trying to catch, no coordination at all. For me funniest of the three was Hooda. Only 4 runs came off the 1st over.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/6UpO9Tj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manan Vohra debuting for Punjab scored 12 runs off of Jhye Richardson, who was also debuting for Punjab, which popped all important question, would Jhye score a 50 in his debut game?
The 4 the over brought the first breakthrough, Arshdeep caught an amazing catch to dismiss Manan Vohra, more than the catch, the reaction Arshdeep gave was what got me.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/KS0BnP3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To me Sanju Samson and Jos Buttler opening the batting for Rajasthan is the best case scenario but for that to happen the middle order needs to be settled too which has not been the case for a while now, so when Buttler and Sanju joined the forces within powerplay it was like a dream come through.
Riley Meridith was brought in for the 5th, he can clock 140ks with ease, but the thing with Jos Buttler is the best English batsman for a reason, he smashed 4 consecutive 4s in that over, I was hoping 6 of them, it was fun anyways. Posing another question, would Jhye and Meridith reach 50 together in their debut game?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preity Zinta 100% would have been like&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;lt;br&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RoxIttP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of powerplay Rajasthan were 59/2, 15 runs ahead of Punjab, but the only catch was Punjab’s bowlers were of way better quality than Rajasthan.
Also in the &lt;strong&gt;8th over&lt;/strong&gt; a big big blow for RR, Jhye Richardson got the big wicket of Buttler. It was actually absolutely brilliant from the guy. First ball of the over he changed pace of ball brilliantly, first ball he bowled to Jos was 131, whereas the yorker that brought the wicket was bowled at around 110.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The match slowly getting out of hands for Rajasthan but the end of 13th over, required run rate went from 12 to 13.43, Dube got out. Samson was still there, but he can’t win you games single handedly ma, its too difficult to do that, support is always important. Parag came in, it was kind of the turning point really, because Parag was about to do something super special. Rajasthan went all guns blazing, scoring 13, 13 and 20 runs of the 14th, 15th and 16th over. Parag was at 25(9), he was on fire yesterday.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parag to leg spinners&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/EytDoCz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;48 runs of 24 balls, it looked like it was even again, but Punjab have this amazing bowler in their team called Mohammad Shami, who was not ready to give it away just yet, he came in took the wicket of Parag, Parag was extremely disappointed with that, Shami even gave away just 8 runs that over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 40 off 18, slightly skewed towards Punjab, but then again Samson was still batting, Jhye Richardson came to bowl and Sanju took him for absolute cleaners, 19 runs came off of that over, and equation came down to 21 of 12 balls. This game had everything, match take sharp turns every over. Looked like Sanju was going to win it for them here, but Meridith who bowled the 19th over wasn’t going to back down before he got his redemption after being smashed 4 consecutive 4s in first over.
He only gave away 8 runs in that over, think about it, 19th over of the game, arguably the most important one, only 8 runs given, pressure was completely back on Rajasthan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arshdeep no doubt had been absolutely magnificent for Punjab, he had done enough to be trusted to bowl in any situation, but I still had thought Punjab probably had made a mistake by bowling him in 14th over, it can also be argued that Punjab wanted to get over the game quickly, with them having gotten a wicket at that point, they wanted to get one more, these things are nice to talk in hindsight, but very difficult to implement on the field.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/xVHeQCZ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
But arshdeep was excellent, he knew his plans, he knew exactly what he wanted to do, nailed it to perfection.
Only 2 runs came of the first 3 balls, equation had come down to 11 of 3, needed a boundary there and Sanju Samson played one of the best lofted cover drive you can imagine, it was nice to see rahul keeping when that played shot as he is the lofted cover drive king.
The next ball, he could not find the gap, Morris ran all the way near Sanju for a single but Sanju was in no mood of that, Morris was super angry at that but in my mind it was the right decision, given the situation and flow, Sanju had a higher probability of hitting a six than Morris. The last ball of the over, bowled exactly where Sanju would’ve liked, but he just could not connect, maybe it was Arshdeep’s plan because he did say after game that plan was to feed them wider balls, but in the end an it was a loss for Rajasthan, extremely disappointed for them, but we got to watch Sanju’s greatness which I always love.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If any of you try to belittle or start trolling him later I will bring my Linus Tech Tips on&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/BzujQWk.png&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;man of the match was given to Sanju, which I am not 100% in denial of, he was magnificent but for me it was Deepak Hooda, the man was brilliant, it reminded me of the time Moeen Ali scored 65(29), as I said earlier I am heavily biased towards English cricketers and that innings was one of my favourites so I will be mentioning them every time I get a chance to.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bAOCUhi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main takeaways, fun events which happened:
Deepak Hooda the batsman has finally been noticed by us all
Arshdeep’s rise as a bowler has been brilliant and I am absolutely loving it.
Rahul Tewatia took an absolute stunner yesterday which reminded me of watching that kind of catch for the first time pulled off by David Hussey, you can check it out if you want to too &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/craNLOfy8l?amp=1&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Sanju Samson does not get affected by captaincy burden at all.
Not confirmed yet, but we might see 2018 Rahul back.
Sunil Gavaskar saying “Who da man” as a pun with the name Hooda in a West Indies accent was the best thing ever.
One thing which I did not touch upon was Punjab’s fielding was pretty bad, they dropped a lot, no coordination between fielders, hopefully they get better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sammith S Bharadwaj</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I am a guy who is heavily biased towards English criketers, I absolutely love them and given Rajasthan Royals is filled with English influence, it won’t come as a surpise whom I was supporting today, but enough of my preference, lets get to the game here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SRH V KKR, please do not forget to take DK with you</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/12/SRHVKKR.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SRH V KKR, please do not forget to take DK with you" /><published>2021-04-12T07:12:23+05:30</published><updated>2021-04-12T07:12:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/12/SRHVKKR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/12/SRHVKKR.html">&lt;p&gt;KKR and SRH have kind of a weird history between each other, KKR have always had a better edge over SRH, winning 12 out of the 19 encounters, but SRH either knocked KKR out in playoffs multiple times, last 2 seasons KKR missed berth in playoff because of SRH, in 2018, SRH beat KKR in the playoff 2 to reach final, very interesting rivalry.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KKR to SRH for knocking them out of playoffs every year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/le66BFa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Both the teams playing 11 were super interesting. SRH were very weird in their selection where they went with Warner, Jonny, Nabi and Rashid as this OS player, leaving out Williamson and Holder. Everyone thought playing Williamson over Jonny at number 4 was the obvious choice but Morgan won’t really mind if they play Jonny at number 4, in fact in my honest opinion, if he would have won game for SRH, Morgan would have happily taken the loss. Now onto KKR, they picked Morgan, Russel, Shakib and Cummins as their OS picks, with KKR finding an Indian mystery spinner in Varun, its not the best strategy to play Narine, also Narine has had a dip in his form too. As KP pointed out in Select Dugout that you are essentially wasting your OS spot playing Narine when you have Bhajji and Varun. KKR’s love for Shakib was pretty evident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me just get straight to the standout moment of the game, which happened even before the game started, it was Russel’s hair, have no idea what he was trying to do there.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Mh73EJL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game was happening in Chennai, what we had observed in the previous game which happened here i.e RCB V KKR was that if you are medium pacer with good pace and can hit the hard length it was going to be full party for you.
SRH bowlers were absolutely brilliant the first 3 overs, giving away just 19 runs, but within that we had seen glimpses of Rana and it continued in the 4th over where he hit 3 consecutive balls for 4 against Sandeep Sharma, to be fair Sandeep did not try at all to attack Rana with short deliveries. First ball of the 4th over was smoked by Gill for a six, it was a no look shot, it is becoming very popular these days. At the end of 5th over KKR were looking really good, 45/0, Mohammad Nabi was brought in for 6th and final over of the powerplay, even though he was hit for a boundary on the second ball of the over, he pulled things back brilliantly giving away just 5 runs.
At the end of powerplay KKR were 50/0, a brilliant start, need to make most use of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this game was actually extremely hyped because of Rashid Khan, few days back &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cricxtasy.com&quot;&gt;CricXtasy&lt;/a&gt; released an article on how to play Rashid Khan, it was incredible with lots and lots of data and details, today the author released a short video kind of showing how good Rashid is with his variations, you can check out the video or the blog using the below.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/g4TVWCOI3S?amp=11&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/flighted_leggie/status/1381053868272848898?s=20&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that was talked about was how to score runs, one way which has been super productive is a slog sweep with batsmen striking those at around 251, a small sample size yes, but you have to deal with it somehow, if it means throwing your wicket away so be it, it is as likely that you will get out to Rashid by playing a normal as much as it is by trying to smash him, you can reduce risks on either ends by being smart but I am just giving a average case here.
Gill tried to slog sweep Rashid, who bowled a googly, now by the looks of Shubhman had actually picked the googly, but I don’t know if he second guessed himself or he did not predict the height ball would properly, his leg position changed at the, he missed it completely and got bowled.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rashid Khan bowling to batsmen who absolutely no clue what he is bowling is like&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/t1NfR1q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rashid is a genius&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now enough of Rashid Khan, moving on, KKR just used the simple strategy everyone else uses, play out Rashid smash everyone else, that is exactly what KKR did here. Rahul Tripathi was absolutely brilliant here, he also reached the milestone of 1000 runs which was nice. His batting reminded most of us of the 2017 season, where he had an amazing season.
Rana also joined the party, Rana was trying out everything out there, when bowlers did not allow him to play conventional shots to score runs, he went on to try playing scoops, reverse sweeps, reverse scoops, lot of them did not come out, lot of them, which was super fun to watch.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ePun5UC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/hEPsVyV.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of 12th everyone thought Bhuvi would br brought to do some magic, but neither was he brought, nor the scoring rate stopped increasing, finally when he was brought for the 15th over, batsmen were well set and it was one of the game changing overs with Rana and Tripathi going all over Bhuvi scoring 19 runs off of that over. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All Bhuvi fans who were expecting him to come and turn the game around&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VpA5IL5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;very sad&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MI struggled to score runs in the final 5 overs and so did KKR at least at the start, Warner had done the sensible thing of saving Rashid’s over to when Russel would come to bat because Rashid is really good against Russel, it happened in the 16th over itself, which was bowled by Nattu and it was really good, going for just 7 runs and giving them a wicket, Rashid was brought immediately the next over, the first ball was 5 wides, really unfortunate. 2 balls later he trapped the big man Russ.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking wicket of Russel? Rashid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/8xmvN8l.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You know what the crazy part was though, that he gave just 2 more runs after that, so if it weren’t for that 5 wides, it was going to be a 2 runs over, obviously KKR would have had a different approach if not for the wide, but this is just more fun to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The horror was not over for KKR because because Nabi came to bowl the next over and he got 2 wickets in 2 balls of both Rana and Morgan, it looked like another classic KKR collapse, but with DK still there, it wasn’t over yet. Morgan has a terrible record against Nabi, getting out 6 times to him in 8 innings. In the 19th over where Nattu was simply nailing those yorkers, DK managed to get underneath of one of the deliveries and dispatch it for 4. To counter Nattu’s yorkers DK was coming across line bending knees and trying to hit them but it just wasn’t happening, but he was successful in doing that in the final over, where he dispatched Bhivi’s first delivery in that fashion. KKR managed to score 16 runs of the final over, which was superb considering how horrible the first 3 overs of death were. DK has been proving again and again how good a finisher, Kohli please somehow make place for him in the world cup.
KKR ended up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me who knows DK won’t be selected but still hoping he will be looking at they announce Indian t20 squad for world cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RoxIttP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now onto SRH chase, it was almost certain that Bhajju pa was going to be opening the bowling but it was super weird that he did bowl at all after that.In the first over Warner played a loose shot which was almost caught by Pat Cummins, not the idea start.
As it would happen, the second over meant the demise of Warner, Prasidh Krishna was the guy who took the wicket, Warner has been extremely vulnerable when bowled near his abdomen, that is what Prasidh did. To realise how important Warner’s wicket is, Warner has scored 27.6% runs of SRH which is the highest for any player ever in IPL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Warner whenever his team is in trouble and nobody is ready to step up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/0yqQiPx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third over was bowled by Shakib, the guy was playing IPL after a long time and he got the wicket of the very first delivery, Saha dragged one going outside off, onto the wicket, the worst possible starts for SRH. Now Manish Pandey and Jonny Bairstow were on crease, if Clive Llyod was there he probably would have been like “no matter, no matter where you bat man, you will come in during power play”.
KKR did not allow any room to score runs at all, choking SRH in the powerplay, the 6th over was bowled by Cummins with every single one being a har length and it went for just 3 runs. At the end of powerplay SRH were at 35/2, really bad position to be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SRH fans at this situation were like&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/V98XtEw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it possibly looks like game is well out of reach for but that was not going to be the case until Jonny was there, Jonny and Pandey steadied the ship, scoring a boundary every over, making sure required run rate would not go beyond reach, Jonny even had reached his fifty of just 32 balls, but then came the game changing over of Pat Cummins. At the end of 12th over, SRH needed 88 of 48 balls which is not such of a huge deal given both players were well set and they had 8 more wicket, I would say it was 60/40 in favour of KKR at that stage and according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cricket.com&quot;&gt;Cricket.com&lt;/a&gt; it was 56/44 in favour of KKR. He literally held Jonny Bairstow by the throat with him not being able to score even a single run of the 3 balls he faced that over, the pressure got onto him and he gave a straightforward catch to Rana. For me the game shifted completely in favour of KKR, to put a number to it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cricket.com&quot;&gt;Cricket.com&lt;/a&gt; says it shifted to 74% in favour of KKR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SRH is said to have a very fragile middle order but that is not entirely true, they have really good batsman and one of them in Nabi, he did not really get going to day but that happens all the time, its just not your day. One more super important over was the 15th one where Varun Chakravarthi just gave 6 runs. Even though 69 runs required of last 5 overs, SRH had not lost hope, they scored 12 runs of the next 5 balls which was on par with what the required run rate was, but a big blow came with Prasidh Krishna claiming wicket of Mohammad Nabi with a slower one, varying pace, works like a charm in these crunch situations.
After this wicket SRH made the weirdest decisions of all, sending in Shankar ahead of Rashid and Samad, who both have a history of smashing well, smashing hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Warner when asked why he sent Shankar before Samad&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ItI776j.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russel bowled the all important 18th over and boy oh boy did he deliver, not only did he just concede 6 runs, he also got the wicket of Vijay Shankar, now how much negative impact did that have for KKR is debatable but still.
With 38 runs required of 12 balls, it was assumed it was done and dusted but for Samad it wasn’t he went to onto smash 2 sixes off of Cummins’ bowling, Samad has till now smashed a six off of bowling of the best of the best of IPL, Nortje, Rabada, Cummins as well as Bumrah!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samad when team’s frontline bowler starts bowling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/FEEk7my.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It was too late to make a difference as SRH needed 22 runs of the last over and SRH could only score 11 that too because of last ball six.
Now one of the biggest question marks which is going to be debated a lot in Manish Pandey’s innings. Now on paper Pandey and Jonny have very similar SR, why only target Pandey, 2 reasons for that, first of all Jonny was on 55(36) before Cummins started his fast bowling masterclass to dismiss him, second his strike rate was 138 at the end of 13th over after which your SR is expected to improve. Third, Pandey’s strike rate reached 138 because of last ball six and if not for that his SR was 128 which is not ideal. Now I will give him a little bit of lineance here, he hadn’t played a professional game for a while, but I for sure expect a lot more from him.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ds6jZ7K.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main takeaways, fun events which happened:
KKR love Shakib and if you are not happy about that, sad for you.
KKR should stop changing stuff and just simply use DK as a finisher.
Russel as a bowler is as important as Russel the batsman.
Everyone forgot Bhajju pa even existed after his first over.
Morgon forgot to count him while naming the OS players for his team.
If used effectively Rahul Tripathi is extremely useful.
One more extremely interesting and fun thing that happened was Warner sent Shankar over obvious choice Samad in that situation, Rohit Sharma did something similar with DK and Dk was the wicket keeper of the opposition this game.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DK, Sharma ji and Mushfiqur Rahim, looking at Warner who thought plan was going to work&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RAB9Pky.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sammith S Bharadwaj</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">KKR and SRH have kind of a weird history between each other, KKR have always had a better edge over SRH, winning 12 out of the 19 encounters, but SRH either knocked KKR out in playoffs multiple times, last 2 seasons KKR missed berth in playoff because of SRH, in 2018, SRH beat KKR in the playoff 2 to reach final, very interesting rivalry.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DC V CSK, It was all about Prithvi Show</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/11/DCVCSK-Prithvi-SHOW.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DC V CSK, It was all about Prithvi Show" /><published>2021-04-11T18:50:23+05:30</published><updated>2021-04-11T18:50:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/11/DCVCSK-Prithvi-SHOW</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/11/DCVCSK-Prithvi-SHOW.html">&lt;p&gt;Wankhede is one of the most incredible cricket pitches to bat on, so when Pant decided to choose to field after winning the toss, it came as surprise to nobody.
Now if we talk about teams, with the number of options CSK had there were too many combinations of teams to keep track of, but the one they chose to field was a typical Dhoni 11, choosing players on whom Dhoni has obssesive level of faith in. This game was also the return of Mr. IPL, Suresh Raina which is always nice to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no Rabada or Nortje, this was a relatively way weaker Delhi side than we are going to see in the future games, but in no way shape or form they were a weak side, immense batting depth, power hitters, dashing openers as well as experienced spinners, this is what forms the best 11 of few of the teams, shows how strong a squad they have.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All those who worried about DC without Rabada and Nortje&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/rLCF5YK.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the biggest uncertainities for DC this game was how would Chris Woakes bowl for them, because, he rarely plays the t20 format for England these days and he did not play a single game for England this winter, after bowling his first ball, he had bowled more balls for DC than for England this year. He was getting beautiful swing out there.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSK openers looking how good Avesh and Woakes were:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/le66BFa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact the first 6 overs of the innings were extremely eventful, with lots and lots of stuff happening. The first over started with Woakes beating the outside edge of Gaikwad and in reply him with as sweet a drive you can imagine. Only 5 runs of the over.
Faf Du Plesis was the highest run scorer for CSK last season, how he plays was always going to be crucial for them, but unfortunately as soon as Gaikwad gave strike to Faf in the second over, Avesh Khan got the better of him, ball was a much fuller, close to 140Ks delivery and it was almost a plumb in front. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avesh Khan while coming in to bowl today:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RfAxiGs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To sprinkle salt on those wounds, Gaikwad got out the first ball of the third over, Woakes made proper use of the swing he was getting, bowling proper test match lengths, he was rewarded for that. Last season memories started floating back, but this time they have Raina and Moeen, way better middle order batsmen than they had last time around. It showed too, with Moeen and Raina counterattacking Avesh Khan and Ashwin even though Ashwin was not the matchup which was in favour of them, extracting 19 runs of the 2 overs. They were at 30/2 at the end of 5 overs. Final over was bowled by Tom Curran, the man has the worst economy rate for any bowler in IPL, which is insane, but he was superb in the over giving away just 3 runs. CSK were strangled at 33/2 by the end of powerplay. Not looking good for CSK, but one nice thing was, Raina and Moeen had shown as long as they are there, Ashwin was not going to be a threat for them.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/EytDoCz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even though they had a bad start, CSK were extremely productive in the middle overs, the portion of the game which costed them most of the matches last season. They scored 103 in between 7th and the 15th over which is unreal!!!
Ashwin was torn apart by Moeen and Raina, with 9th over going for 18 runs, yes he got the wicket of Moeen which was extremely crucial at that stage, but still it was a below average performance and it happens and I am sure he will do way better things for DC than this. Amit Mishra had bowled his first two overs relatively well going for only 10 runs, but Raina was in no mood to stop, he scored 14 runs of the first 3 balls of the 12th over of the innings. Things were looking pretty well for CSK and it got even better when Stoinis came in, one of the balls slipped and came over waist length of Rayadu but it was also dispatched for a six by Rayadu, the free hit was a leg bye which went for four. The last ball was pulled away for a six by Raina which brought his 50!!!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extremely contrasting performance in powerplay and middle overs by CSK:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/pjtfiXg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Among all these explosive overs, Tom Curran managed to get wicket of Rayadu and also had given just 7 runs in the 14th over of the match, he was having a really good game till then. The next over by Stoinis went for 12 runs, which ended one of the most insane middle over hitting by a team, given it was done by CSK is even more special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given how good they were in the middle over, it would be a nice assumption that they would do well in the death, at least that’s what we thought. A terrible mix up meant that Raina got run out, he looked so good out there, that probably was only thing that could’ve stopped that man. Biggest talking point of all was that Dhoni had not come in to bat till that point, everyone wanted him at number 4 which did not happen, he sent Rayadu at 5, number 6? Nope Jaddu, which wasn’t even a tactical move with Raina a lefty already there. He came in at number 7, had a brief stay and he got bowled 2nd ball of his innings. Everything was looking really well for DC, with overs 16-18 going for a combined total of just 19 runs.
But it wasn’t all over for CSK, Sam Curran took his elder brother Tom Curran for absolute cleaners. Well Tom had a brilliant day till that over, but a missed full length delivery which was sent went for a six over long on, bouncer directed outside off was smacked for another six, and to top it all off a 4 through covers meant Tom Curran figures went form 3-0-17-1 to 4-0-40-1. Insane how one over can turn around and make everything you did before null and void. 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3UkiHKi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Chris Woakes did a relatively good death bowling than what was expected of him, good running between wickets meant they would score 10 runs of the over, had a happy ending for Woakes though, getting the wicket of Sam Curran.
CSK ended up at 188/7 which was kind of below after looking at CSK’s middle order batting itself, but way way better than they where at then end of powerplay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when the DC innings everyone, it was going to be very very interesting, Prithvi Shaw was coming in after a HULK level domestic season where he flexed how good a player he is, he probably also worked and adjusted the error in his style that was causing him to get out even before he got in at IPL and the international level. But it was not going to be easy given the history of Chahar and Shaw, Shaw had scored 38 runs of 39 balls and had got out 5 times to Chahar before this encounter. But he looked way more comfortable than he ever did. Interesting thing was that last season before the start of a horrid run for Shaw he had scored 66(41) which ensured a win for DC. 
There wasn’t really much to talk about powerplay here, it was just Shaw manhandling CSK bowlers, he smoked the “LORD” Thakur for 3 consecutive boundaries in the 5th over, which was heavily profitable over for DC as 17 runs came off of it.
One other interesting as well as super cool thing was, last season when Shikhar Dhawan scored his first IPL 100 which was against CSK, he had scored one six, that too to Sam Curran it was just him extending his hands and hitting straight above bowlers head, in the 3rd over, he smashed a six which looked very very similar, only difference was Dhawan had his legs wide apart last season.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six from IPL 2020&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/A00fgSF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six from IPL 2021&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/G1s1oQ9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSK still have still not got a breakthrough by the way, DC were just on cruise mode, scoring at least a boundary every over.
The thing which was most interesting was that Dwayne Bravo was not brought in till the 14th over, which was extremely interesting, now this strategy works well when you have got wickets in the start, DJ Bravo is one of the champions of t20 cricket, extreme utility player, specialises at death but can bowl anywhere, you would assume Dhoni would have brought him in before but he didn’t. 
3rd ball of his first over, he took the wicket of ever dangerous Shaw, who was looking well set for an incredible 100. That over just went for 3 runs and a wicket, just for some more perspective than necessary about how good that over was for CSK, DC had scored 15 runs of the previous over and of the previous 5 overs DC had scored 51 runs.
But it was kind of little too late, runs flow did not stop at all.
Even though Shardul Thakur(LORD) got the wicket of Dhawan on 3rd ball of 17th over, he already had leaked 9 runs of the first 2 deliveries and required run rate was almost 6. It was only a matter of time DC would win.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/oSHBG2w.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main takeaways:&lt;/strong&gt;
Prithvi Shaw and his show stopping batting, hope he continues to do that.
Dhawan the run machine is still going strong, he keeps getting better and better every year, amazing to watch.
Chris Woakes has shown he has the t20 game in him and if need be he can be a replacement for South Africans without affecting the bowling by a lot.
Tom Curran’s death bowling is still under a lot of questioning, he was brilliant the fist three overs, but all went down in the last one, death bowling which was the reason he got selected to the England teams has become his weaker point.
Sam Curran has shown he can bat superbly well at the back end of the innings, which is a great sign for CSK as well as England, bowling still questionable, but hey! one problem at a time.
Delhi Capitals were superbly lucky Avesh Khan and Chris Woakes were that economical, we do not know if they can sustain it, but if they do, its looking all well and good for Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sammith S Bharadwaj</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Wankhede is one of the most incredible cricket pitches to bat on, so when Pant decided to choose to field after winning the toss, it came as surprise to nobody. Now if we talk about teams, with the number of options CSK had there were too many combinations of teams to keep track of, but the one they chose to field was a typical Dhoni 11, choosing players on whom Dhoni has obssesive level of faith in. This game was also the return of Mr. IPL, Suresh Raina which is always nice to see.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RCB V MI, not for the weak hearted</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/10/rcbvmi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RCB V MI, not for the weak hearted" /><published>2021-04-10T18:50:23+05:30</published><updated>2021-04-10T18:50:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/10/rcbvmi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/samsblog/jekyll/update/2021/04/10/rcbvmi.html">&lt;p&gt;At around 7:15, I just got out of a high intensity college quiz just to realise RCB won the toss, Kohli winning the toss, how rare is that??? Jokes aside, RCB won the toss and chose to field, it wasn’t the decision the commentators liked the most, they thought it would be better of fielding. Now the thing is, the match is happening in Chennai, there is always chance of dew, also Mumbai has always struggled first match every season, they have not won the first game for a long long time now, so putting them to bat was actually a pretty smart move. Let’s start talking about the game.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/CIIc4te.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lets talk about the selection, the thing is Kohli loves Saini and it wouldn’t have been a wrong assumption that he would have played but that was not the case, Harhsal Patel the man who was traded was playing the first game, I absolutely love that guy, he even played for RCB before, so it was more like a homecoming. MI went on to bring in Marco Jansen instead of normal choice NCN, it also maybe because of the love MI has for left arm seamers. RCB even chose to play Rajat Patidar, that man has been brilliant in the practice matches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QDK was in quarantine which meant LYNNSANITY was getting his debut for MI. You would expect Virat to start with a spinner given Lynn struggles a lot and Rohit in the recent past has struggled to pick the line.
Well that really didn’t happen with Virat starting with Siraj, but that wasn’t a bad move with RCB pacers being brilliant at the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RCB started absolutely incredibly, they gave away only 12 runs in the first three overs. In the third over, Sharma ji played a brilliant shot but it looked like it almost went to hands of Jamieson, not his fault though, Jamieson is a 6’8 beast.
For the fourth over, Kohli decided to go with Chahal, it wouldn’t have been the obvious choice of anybody. Chahal is the frontline middle overs bowlers and has won many games for RCB that way and I intend to see him being used in that way, its not like they didn’t have option, Jamieson is a really good power play bowler, Siraj is too and they also have the greatest of them all Sundar.
He got smoked for 12 runs in the first 5 balls but that doesn’t mean there wasn’t a silver lining, there obviously was which was a mixup causing Rohit to get run out. Really an unfortunate event, but a success nevertheless.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jp4A1Ba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the thing Surya Kumar Yadav has done 6 times in the last 11 times he has batted is start the innings with a boundary. So when Jamieson bowled to SKY, it would’ve been a nice assumption that he would start with that and boy oh boy he did, it was absolutely an incredible shot. The main strength of Chris Lynn is his powerplay hitting, he is extremely destructive but he still had not come to his own, maybe the pitch played a role, maybe the line and length of balls were pitch perfect. MI were 30/1 at end of 5 overs which is not really the best stage to be in, but it is what it is.
If one over of smashing was not enough Kohli brought in Chahal again, &lt;strong&gt;I am sorry but using your best middle overs bowler in a totally different place where you know he is not as effective is not really the thing I am into&lt;/strong&gt;, it caused a glimpse of LYNNSANITY
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RoxIttP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That 11 run over kind of started a run flow, Virat brouhgt Shahbaz for 7th over, finally!! But by that time LYNN was already ready to smash anything and everything around him. That over costed us 14 runs.
Now they were in full flow, MI accumulated 42 runs after the powerplay in just 3 over which is jut insane!!
SKY and Lynn together scored of 15 runs of Harshal Pate.
In that time SKY played his signature drive but also we to say Patel was very unlucky, RCB managed to drop catches, misfielding, in fact those extras are the reason the might possibly have potentially caused RCB to lose the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/TsmbRUW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Kohli brings back Chahal for the 10th over, I have always believed Chahal should bowl in the middle or death, he is brilliant there, do not waste him in the powerplay, he only gave 3 runs in the 10th over, which shifted back the momentum towards RCB, and immediately the next over they got the results, Jamieson got the wicket of Suryakumar, but before that, he just simply flicked one for a massive six which was just insane. RCB continued their hold with Siraj anna giving away only 4 runs the next over. The pressure built up caused another wicket to fall, with Lynn getting out at 49 to Sundar. Still don’t understand why Kohli does not trust Sundar in the powerplay, interestingly I had completely forgot he was even playing till that over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The match went from 30/1 at the end of 5 overs to 83/1 at the end of 9 overs, and then RCB had sort of a comeback to bring it down to 105/3 at the end of 13 overs. The game had chunks of over being controlled by both teams, with each teams getting ahead of each other for 4-5 overs and then the other team pulling it back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immediate over was bowled by Chahal, Kishan for whom it was a profitable matchup unleashed all over Chahal, scoring 15 runs from it.Dan Christian who for me is the x-factor for RCB bowled the next over, he might not have had the ideal game, but he is going to win them multiple games in the future.
Hardik Pandya absolutely smoked one viciously for four on the second ball of the 15th over, but then Dan pulled it back giving away only 8 runs in the over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the death, where the real game starts. Mumbai are well above average team with the bat throughout the game, but where they really win games, is the death, last season they were head and shoulders above every other team, I mean it wasn’t even close, one of the main reason was Pollard and Hardik batting alot in those situations, with one of them there you would think fireworks, but to be that day, Harshal Patel was absolutely brilliant that over, not allowing the batsmen to do anything, Pandya still got cheeky and carved one for four, but at the end Harshal Patel got the better of him and got his wicket. For me this 16th over was the turning point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siraj anna was brought in for his final over for the 17th over, at that moment I did not think it was the right move bowling him at death and he even got hit for a four in the first ball, at the end of 2 balls he had already gone for 6 runs and Pollard coming on strike you would think its all over for Siraj, but nope!! Siraj was brilliant, Pollard at the start of his innings struggles when the ball is pitch short on to his body, that’s what Siraj did, one of them even hit the abdomen area of Pollard too. He gave away only 8 runs!!! Incredible growth shown by Siraj anna, his 4 overs went for only 22 runs, no wickets but if one player can bowl with level of economy I wouldn’t really care. The growth of Siraj has been brilliant to see.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/HfzA3eO.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time RCB did not let go of the momentum they created at all, Harshal Patel came fo the 18th over, took a wicket of Ishan Kishan, it was an eventful one too, umpire gave it not out and ABD went straight away for a review, he was so so confident about it. Harshal gave away only 4 runs, absolutely brilliant stuff. Funny thing was, a catch was dropped the delivery before Kishan got out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamieson came back for the 19th over, Krunal smashed one, but it went right towards Kohli, maybe he couldn’t gauge the speed at which it was coming, it went right through his hands to smashed his eyes, it got real red real quick, luckily it wasn’t major injury. 3rd ball of the over went for a four, not only that, it was a no ball because RCB only had 3 fielders inside the circle, free hit did not do much damage for RCB, but for Krunal it did, because Jamieson nailed a yorker which broke Krunal’s bat. The over went for 12 runs, but with previous 3 overs going only for 12 runs, it didn’t affect them much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I say that, the previous over probably would’ve affected the result if not for one of the greatest death over bowling by Harshal Patel. Harshal Patel got the wickets of Krunal as well as Pollard on the first two balls of the over which was absolutely incredible and it did not stop there. Marco Jansen the debutant, was bamboozled by a yorker on the 4th ball of the final over. The final ball Mumbai tried to run 2 and got run out, so in short the last over of the innings RCB took 4 wickets and gave only 1 run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was actually &lt;strong&gt;first time ever that a bowler took a 5-fer against the mighty Mumbai&lt;/strong&gt; which is insane. It was brilliant bowling performance, especially by Harshal who made a major comeback, he had gone for 15 runs in his first over and ended up with figures of 4-0-27-5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/pjtfiXg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Now lets talk about the RCB innings which was super super interesting, we all knew Kohli was opening but without Devdutt Paddikal, it was going to be interesting, I always wanted to see how Sundar would do opening and RCB did exactly that, they sent him to open the innings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boult bowling the first was insane, the amount of swing he was getting was absolutely incredible. Rohit dropped the second ball of the innings, it was something about captain’s dropping catches. There even was 5 wides so 10 runs of the first over, not the ideal start for MI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But MI have the greatest bowler to have ever existed Jasprit Bumrah and he was brilliant, normally we see MI to bowl, bat poor in the first game of the season, one of the reason for poor bowling is normally Bumrah leaking runs, but this time it looked different, Bumrah was at his pure best here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boult started the 3rd over, on the second ball of the over, Kohli played the classic drive which was like “ganga snana” for eyes, it was like all my sins were getting sucked out of me. But after that Boult was superb, gave away only 6 runs in the over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RCB were 21/0 at the end of 3 overs. It got really better in the next over.
Marco Jansen was given the 4th over and Kohli pulled one for four immediately, no mercy at all, 14 runs came of that over and RCB at 35/0 at the end of 4 overs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krunal was brought up, Mumbai kind of use him brilliantly, but with Sundar having the profitable matchup, he was always going to go hard, he did but unfortunately that meant he got out first ball he faced, but not a huge deal because his whole role is to utilise powerplay, so hit out or get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last over of powerplay, Boult was brought back for a third over, over started with a boundary, but he was brilliant after that, he brought out a knuckle ball to get wicket of Rajat Patidar, nobody had any idea Boult had a knuckle ball it was an awesome scene. At the end of powerplay 46/2, 5 runs ahead of MI, but the match still even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When matchup is in favour that is him bowling to left handers he is next level brilliant, which is the reason even when he goes for runs against lefties, his economy is kind of evened out. He bowled the 7th over which went for only 4 runs. Krunal is a very smart bowler I don’t know why people kind of don’t like him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/tjvUu47.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Rahul Chahar came in for the 8th over and Maxwell loves leg spinner, yes they turn away from him, but it allows him to play the classic Maxi reverse sweep and he did do that the first ball itself, the over was super productive for RCB scoring 13 runs. After a few lean overs it was very essential at that stage.Any kind of leg spinner comes in and Maxwell is like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/PwSlY5r.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Krunal came back for the 9th over and again as at his best, going for just 6 runs, that too because of a boundary on the last ball. 69/2 at the end of 9overs, i.e at the stage of strategic timeout MI were 83/1, 14 runs behind but with the brilliant big hitters RCB, game hadn’t really slipped away. For the 10th over Jansen was brought and he was really good, not giving anything to batsman to pounce on, One ball actually supposed to go for four, but Suryakumar did an absolutely incredible to stop that.
So at the end of 10 overs, 75/2, 11 runs behind MI at that stage, they were 11 runs ahead at end of 5th over, t20 is the most finicky game of all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krunal for the 11th over and Maxwell smoked one for massive six, now if you thought, nice! game is on, RCB can score more than 12 runs that over, nope! he gave only 3 runs after that, which meant only 9 runs even after the first ball being a six, incredible stuff. RCB are 84/2 at this stage.
Maxwell and reverse sweeps are the true love story, you just can’t keep them apart, he smashed first ball of Chahar for one six that way, 11 runs came of that way. RCB were coming back in the game superbly, but Sharma ji did the big brain move, the perfect utilisation of Bumrah, 1 in pp, 1 in middle and 2 at death, I don’t think any other team can afford to do that with their best bowler, only DC is the team that comes to mind. Bumrah came, in his classic fashion, took wicket of Kohli, gave away only 4 runs, what else shall I say, this has happened too many times to require an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now RCB need 61 runs of 42 balls, even though a wicket just fell, RCB are well in the game and the next 2 overs were going to be crucial before death overs started.
Chahar who had been below par at best till that point, bowled an absolutely incredible over giving away just 4 runs in the over, RCB had just scored 8 runs of the last 2 overs and even lost a wicket, if you thought horror was over, the newbie Jansen got the wicket of Maxwell at the very first ball of his over!!!. He got the wicket at last ball of the over too, crazy stuff was happening out there, with MI and RCB playing each other, it always happens. I know MI has won way more, but that doesn’t mean the matches haven’t been fun, they always have, no ball saga, Yuvraj hat trick sixes, Nehra going full bobble head to make Negi bowl, which backfired terribly, Pollard and Kishan almost taking them home last season scoring 89 in last 5 overs, Suryakumar Kohli staring contest, Kohli-ABD 200 run partnership, full thrills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/OPh9EXA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Chahar was brought back in for the 16th over and ABD started fireworks, 6 and 4 of the first 2 balls of the over, 15 runs came of the over.
It all looked done for MI, until Bumrah came back next over, nailing those yorkers, taking wicket of Dan with a short one and going for only 5 runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/XgppZwU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
34 off 18 balls, with Boult, Bumrah and Jansen, looked tight, but there was the Master ABD for whom impossible is nothing.
Boult is not the best death overs t20 bowler, even when he had the season to remember last time, he wasn’t brilliant in death. His lengths weren’t as good but still. 15 runs came of his and the equation was now 19 of 12 with one over for Bumrah and one for Jansen.
Now the first thought anyone would have it play out Bumrah, try to score 8-9 runs and smash the young guy, I would think that but ABD was in no mood of that, he scored off 11 runs in the first 4 balls itself. With Jamieson in for the last 2 balls the obvious thought should have been Jamieson will smash last two balls, what happens will happen, ABD should be on strike last over, but for some reason they ran on 5th ball which was a run out by the way, bringing back ABD to strike on last ball. They did get a single and ABD came back on strike the last over but still, you try to reduce the risks to as low values as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABD ran a single on the first ball of the over, with only 7 runs required RCB could afford to do that and Harshal Patel being a more than an average batsman helps too, ABD showing faith boosted his confidence alot and they ran 2 the immediate ball after that bringing it down to 4 of 4 balls, the game was next level fun, a single brought back ABD on strike, its 3 of 3 balls. ABD hits, tries to run a double and gets run out! It was terrible running, reminiscent of the Chris Jordan run that caused the double super over last season against the same opposition. Siraj was on strike now with 2 of 2 required, perfect season opener, Siraj ran a single on a leg bye, more like they sneaked a run, but that’s what you need to do in these crunch situation right.
Harshal Patel just nudged on to win it for RCB. Harshal Patel scoring the winning runs was the perfect finish I needed.
It was also a testament of how important ABD is for RCB, I still wonder how they haven’t won a single cup even with him, he truly deserves it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/9V6rTLR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Let us wrap it off with some important, some fun and some interesting things that happened,
Krunal flexing how smart of a bowler he is.
Marco Jansen kind of announcing himself.
Harshal Patel showing he can be the death over guy for RCB in these conditions.
Chris Lynn ran his captain out, Maxwell almost ran his captain out, both debuting for their franchises too.
Proving again and again that RCB V MI is the real thrilling game, not any other game.
Swanny saying it was Maxwell’s highest score in the last to years when he was at 10 was the funniest thing ever.
Shahbaz Ahmad was called Nadeem by the announcer.
Last year Saurabh Tiwary was brought in because Kishan was unavailable, he top scored MI lost, the same thing has happened here but with Lynn.
Running between the wickets of RCB was incredible, it was one of the reason they were in the game the whole time.
RCB really need to improve catching and fielding, they missed a lot of chances which is why even with terrible batting MI reached 158.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sammith S Bharadwaj</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">At around 7:15, I just got out of a high intensity college quiz just to realise RCB won the toss, Kohli winning the toss, how rare is that??? Jokes aside, RCB won the toss and chose to field, it wasn’t the decision the commentators liked the most, they thought it would be better of fielding. Now the thing is, the match is happening in Chennai, there is always chance of dew, also Mumbai has always struggled first match every season, they have not won the first game for a long long time now, so putting them to bat was actually a pretty smart move. Let’s start talking about the game.</summary></entry></feed>